LEO HUSSAIN

• DETAILS •

PROFILE

London +447903000606 github.com/leohussain

leo.94@hotmail.co.uk

o SKILLS o

ArcGIS

QGIS

Python

Project Management

Client Liaison

R

SQL

JavaScript

HTML & CSS

Django

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

Microsoft Office

HOBBIES

Running

Cooking

Gaming

GIS specialist with an MSc in Geographical Information Science from UCL and a BSc in Geography from King's College London. I have attained a variety of technical skills, geared toward creativity and development, and have successfully applied these skills to many forms of geospatial analysis and data. I have a deep interest in mapping and data handling and goals to broaden my knowledge and become a professional expert in the field of GIS. My key strengths are in graphic and cartographic design, python, data processing and spatial analysis.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Geospatial Market Analyst at Oasis Hub Ltd, London

April 2019 — December 2020

Geospatial Data Management & Services: Management of all data, metadata, and services on website. Responsible for ongoing new data discoveries. Broadened knowledge of available catastrophe data for consulting and value-added service application. Maintenance of GeoServer. Created maps and visualised spatial data for sampling commercial data and marketing.

Website Administration & Marketing: Task coordinator for all web development and site maintenance. Reported monthly analytics and stats. Updates to CRM system. Graphic design for web/social marketing material using Photoshop and organisational press/report documents. Created blog posts, custom web pages and newsletters via Mailchimp.

Project Management: Project manager of the Oasis-CAIMAN project, a collaboration between Oasis Hub Ltd and Cranfield University, funded by Innovate UK. Communicated with insurance claims adjusters and academics for product R&D. Designed technical specifications for a mobile application and web frontend. Designed project timeline, CRM and Gantt charts for review reporting.

Client Liaison: Being the face for customer service and client liaison. Experienced in communicating climate change and disaster data to Insurtech, large banks, consultancies and retail/distribution corporations, among others. Partook in an EU Horizon 2020 project, collaborating with 23 universities and SME's across Europe, which delivered climate-change risk data through the Oasis Hub portal.

Part-time Work at Amazon, Tesco, Sainsbury's & Domino's Pizza

March 2013 — December 2018

Voluntary GIS Technician at Mapping4Change Ltd

May 2017 — July 2017

Assisting the completion of mapping and analysis of research for multiple humanitarian projects.

EDUCATION

MSc Geographical Information Science at University College London (UCL)

September 2017 — September 2018

BSc Geography at King's College London

September 2014 — July 2017

Certificate of Higher Education in Social Sciences at Birkbeck University of London

September 2013 — July 2014

COURSES

Python for Everybody Specialisation, University of Michigan

- · Python Data Structures
- · Using Python to Access Web Data
- Using Databases with Python
- · Capstone: Retrieving, Processing, and Visualizing Data with Python

This Specialization introduced me to programming concepts including data structures, networked application program interfaces, and databases, using the Python programming language. My projects in his course included using the Google PageRank Algorithm to understand search engine basics, retrieving, cleaning and modelling data from Google Geodata API and in-browser map visualisation using Google Maps API.

Web Design for Everybody Specialisation, University of Michigan

2020

- Introduction to HTML5 & CSS3
- Interactivity with JavaScript
- Advanced Styling with Responsive Design
- Web Design for Everybody Capstone Project

This Specialization covered writing syntactically correct HTML5 and CSS3 and creating interactive web experiences with JavaScript. Also, developing high quality web sites that, work seamlessly on mobile, tablet, and large screen browsers accessible. During the capstone I developed a professional-quality web portfolio demonstrating my growth in web development and my knowledge of accessible web design.

Django For Everybody Specialisation, University of Michigan

2020

- Building Web Applications in Django
- Django Features and Libraries
- Using Javascript, JQuery & JSON in Django

This specialization introduced me to building responsive websites using the Django library.

★ PROJECTS

Development of a Mobile App for Rough Sleeper Data

2018

SKILLS USED: Javascript, HTML, Github, Node.js, PostGreSQL

Developed an android app (full stack) to display and map the locations of rough sleeper hotspots reported within the last 30 days, to be used by outreach workers.

Exploratory Analysis of Rough Sleeper Data in London

2018

SKILLS USED: Spatial Analysis, Temporal Trend Analysis, Spatial Auto-correlation & Moran's I

Explored open-source annual rough sleeper data and its correlations with socio-economic variables from the 2011 census, at London borough level.

Spatial Database Management

2018

SKILLS USED: PostGIS, SQL, FME, QGIS

Created a spatial database with WKT entries from scratch, including 3D spatial objects which loaded into FME to represent buildings and architectural structures.

Sustainable Food Production in the East of England

2017

SKILLS USED: Mapping, Spatial Data Analysis, Linear Regression Modelling

Produced maps of past & current agricultural(arable) activity and its effects on river water quality. Future projections were calculated and mapped factoring in climate change effects and potential limitations imposed on crop production.

Identifying Nutritional Gaps in Rough Sleepers in San Francisco

2015

SKILLS USED: Graduated Mapping, Heat Mapping, Spatial Regression

Identified spatially and statistically, the relationship between rough sleepers, food accessibility and facility availability in San Francisco to investigate if there are nutritional gaps in homeless people depending on where in the city they choose to stay.

1 REFERENCES

References available upon request